Guide to the Erwin Cotton Mills records, 1832-1976 and undated, bulk 1892-1967 RL.00366
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Account books series, 1892-1967; 2
  - Inventories, 1893-1967; 11
    - Mills 2, 5, 1965 July 3 (Box 20)
    - Mill 3, 1965 July 3 (Box 20)
    - Mill 8, 1965 July 3 (Box 20)
    - Mills 3, 8, 1965 Oct. 2 (Volume 272)
    - Mills 1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 1965 Oct. 2 (Volume 273)
    - Mills 2, 5, 1966 Jan. 1 (Box 20)
    - Mill 3, 1966 Jan. 1 (Box 20)
    - Mill 8, 1966 Jan. 1 (Box 20)
    - Mills 1, 4, 6, 1966 Apr. 2 (Box 21)
    - Mills 2, 5, 1966 Apr. 2 (Box 21)
    - Mill 3, 1966 Apr. 2 (Box 21)
    - Mill 8, 1966 Apr. 2 (Box 21)
    - Mills 1, 4, 6, 1966 July 2 (Box 21)
    - Mills 2, 5, 1966 July 2 (Box 21)
    - Mill 3, 1966 July 2 (Box 21)
    - Mill 8, 1966 July 2 (Box 21)
    - Mills 2, 3, 5, 8, 1966 Dec. 31 (Box 21)
    - General inventory, 1967 Apr. 1 (Box 21)
  - Payroll Records, 1933-1964; 12
    - Distribution of payrolls, 1933-1943 (Volume 274)
    - Payroll journal, 1944-1952 (Volume 275)
    - Payroll journal, 1953-1964 (Volume 276)
    - Check control for workman's compensation insurance, 1956-1960 (Volume 277)
    - Workmen's compensation check register, 1961 (Volume 278)
    - Workmen's compensation check register, 1962 (Volume 279)
    - Payroll letters, 1954 Oct. 2 (Volume 280)
    - Payroll letters, 1955 Jan. 2 (Volume 281)
    - Payroll letters, 1955 Apr. 3 (Volume 282)
    - Payroll letters, 1955 July 3 (Volume 283)
    - Payroll letters, 1955 Oct. 2 (Volume 284)
    - Payroll letters, 1955 Dec. 31 (Volume 285)
    - Payroll letters, 1956 Mar. 31 (Volume 286)
    - Payroll letters, 1956 July 1 (Volume 287)
    - Payroll letters, 1956 Sept. 30 (Volume 288)
    - Payroll letters, 1956 Dec. 30 (Volume 289)
    - Payroll letters, 1957 Mar. 31 (Volume 290)
    - Payroll letters, 1957 June 30 (Volume 291)
    - Payroll letters, 1957 Sept. 30 (Volume 292)
    - Payroll letters, 1957 Dec. 31 (Volume 293)
    - Payroll letters, 1958 Mar. 29 (Volume 294)
    - Payroll letters, 1958 June 28 (Volume 295)
    - Payroll letters, 1958 Sept. 28 (Volume 296)
    - Payroll letters, 1958 Dec. 28 (Volume 297)
    - Payroll letters, 1959 Mar. 28 (Volume 298)
    - Payroll letters, 1959 June 27 (Volume 299)
    - Payroll letters, 1959 Oct. 4 (Volume 300)
    - Payroll letters, 1960 Jan. 3 (Volume 301)
    - Payroll letters, 1960 Apr. 3 (Volume 302)
    - Payroll letters, 1960 July 3 (Volume 303)
    - Payroll letters, 1960 Oct. 2 (Volume 304)
    - Payroll letters, 1961 Jan. 1 (Volume 305)
    - Payroll letters, 1961 Apr. 2 (Volume 306)
    - Payroll letters, 1961 July 2 (Volume 307)
    - Payroll letters, 1961 Sept. 30 (Volume 308)
    - Payroll letters, 1961 Dec. 31 (Volume 309)
    - Payroll letters, 1962 Mar. 31 (Volume 310)
    - Payroll letters, 1962 June 30 (Volume 311)
    - Payroll letters, 1962 Sept. 30 (Volume 312)
    - Payroll letters, 1962 Dec. 31 (Volume 313)
    - Payroll letters, 1963 Mar. 31 (Volume 314)
    - Payroll letters, 1963 June 30 (Volume 315)
    - Payroll letters, 1963 Sept. 30 (Volume 316)
    - Payroll letters, 1963 Dec. 28 (Volume 317)
    - Payroll letters, 1964 Mar. 31 (Volume 318)
    - Payroll letters, 1964 Apr.-June (Volume 319)
  - Miscellaneous Accounts, 1963-1964; 13
    - Ledgers of accounts issued to and completed by accountants, 1963 Aug.-Oct. (Volume 320)
    - Ledgers of accounts issued to and completed by accountants, 1964 Aug.-Oct. (Volume 321)
- Alphabetical series, 1832-1967; 3
  The Alphabetical series consists of randomly surviving files constituting only a small percentage of what were once massive office files. These records span the life of the company and include financial, legal, correspondence, reports, and volumes arranged by topic and name in alphabetical order. There is information about costs, purchases, labor, marketing, income, expenses, profit sharing, equipment and buildings, plant operations, property acquisitions, trade organizations, agencies of the state and national governments, other companies and mills, individuals, and so on.
  The Price Books (Account Books series) and Memorandum Books include production and marketing statistics for Erwin Mills as well as management's memoranda about the statistics and the overall industry.
  Names of mill workers can be found in files for notes receivable, mill house sales, accidents, employee accidents, profit sharing, and elsewhere. Notable files for textile mills owned or controlled by the same interests as Erwin Mills are Alpine Cotton Mills, Durham Cotton Manufacturing Co., Locke Cotton Mills, Oxford Cotton Mills, and the Flint and Co. file.
  - Accident affidavits by employees, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Accident litigation: employee Thomas L. Caves, 1926-1927 (Box 1)
  - Accounting machine, 1955 (approx.) (Box 1)
  - Accounting procedures and forms, 1945-1954 and undated (Box 1)
  - Agricultural Adjustment Act: Statement of K.P. Lewis before the U.S. House Committee on Agriculture, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol problem, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Charles M. vs. Erwin Cotton Mills, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Alpine Cotton Mills financial statements, 1910-1919 (Box 1)
  - American Cotton Manufacturers Association, 1916, 1928 (Box 1)
  - American Cotton Manufacturers Institute reports, 1949-1953 (Box 1)
  - Amortization of war emergency facilities, 1940-1946 (Box 1)
  - Amortization of war emergency facilities: applications, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Annual reports, 1929-1934, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Appraisals and reports, 1928; 9 volumes (Box 2)
  - Architectural design for building by Lee, Smith, and Van DeVoort, Richmond, VA, 1920s (Box 2)
  - Archives: List of Company Records, 1892-1908 (Box 2)
  - Assets: Additions to permanent assets, 1932-1941 (Box 2)
  - Audits and reports, 1915-1946 (Box 3)
  - Audits and reports, 1947-1963 and undated (Box 4)
  - Balance sheets, 1903-1947 (Box 4)
  - Bank of Cooleemee, 1905-1958; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Blueprints of plants, buildings, equipment, etc., in Durham, N.C., 1962-1976 and undated; 6 folders (Oversize-folder 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6)
  - Buildings, machinery, equipment, 1931-1949 (Box 4)
  - Buildings survey and replacement value, 1935-1941 and undated (Box 4)
  - Caldwell County property, 1899 (Box 5)
  - Carolina-Florida Lumber Company memos, 1907 (Box 5)
  - Catawba River Great Falls, Lancaster Co., S.C. deeds and papers, 1832, 1892-1900 (Box 5)
  - Child labor, undated (Box 5)
  - China market including memorandum of Mustard and Co., Shanghai, for British-American Tobacco Co., 1909 (Box 5)
  - Cloth and seconds production, 1933-1938 (Box 5)
  - Cloth woven, 1926-1944 (Box 5)
  - Consolidation proposed for Erwin Group, Springs Group, Thomaston Group, and Riverside and Dan River Group, 1927-1928 (Box 5)
  - Costs, 1907, 1922, 1928, 1930-1931 (Box 5)
  - Cotton futures trading, 1937-1939, 1942-1946; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Cotton Memorandum by K.P. Lewis, 1931 (Box 5)
  - Cotton purchases, 1917 and undated (Box 5)
  - Cotton-Textile Institute, 1927-1928 (Box 5)
  - Cotton-Textile Institute: Reports to, 1944-1948 (Box 5)
  - Coulter, Lowry and Co., Greensboro, N.C.: Goods finished by, 1902 (Box 5)
  - Denim sales and Federal Trade Commission, 1939 (Box 5)
  - Depreciation, 1893-1912 (Box 6)
  - Depreciation: Cost and depreciation reports, 1926 (Box 6)
  - Depreciation: Reconcilement of plant and depreciation accounts, 1925-1931 (Box 6)
  - Depreciation exhibits, 1932-1942 (Box 6)
  - Depreciation exhibits, 1943-1946 (Box 7)
  - Depreciation exhibits and working papers, 1949-1950; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Depreciation regulations, 1934 (Box 7)
  - Depreciation summaries and working papers, 1949-1950; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Depreciation summaries and working papers, 1951-1954; 8 folders (Box 8)
  - Depreciation summaries and working papers, 1955-1957; 8 folders (Box 9)
  - Depreciation summaries and working papers, 1958-1959; 7 folders (Box 10)
  - Depreciation summaries and working papers, 1960-1962; 7 folders (Box 11)
  - Depreciation summaries and working papers, 1962; 9 folders (Box 12)
  - Depreciation summaries and working papers, 1963; 8 folders (Box 13)
  - Depreciation summaries and working papers, 1964; 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Depreciation working papers used for calculation of depreciation under obsolescence basis, 1948-1955 (Box 14)
  - Dividends, 1912-1916, 1922-1941 (Box 15)
  - Dunavent Cotton Manufacturing Co., 1890-1893 (Box 15)
  - Dunbar Farm and Mercantile Co., Edgecombe Co., N.C., 1917-1920 and undated (Box 15)
  - Dunn, N.C.: Real estate transactions, 1926 (Box 15)
  - Dunn, N.C.: Erwin Cotton Mills subdivision map, 1920 (Box 64)
  - Durham and Southern Railway, 1927-1928 (Box 15)
  - Durham Cotton Manufacturing Co.: Financial statements, 1910-1919 (Box 15)
  - Durham Daily Sun: Notice of incorporation of Erwin Cotton Mills, 1892 (Box 15)
  - Dye and Finishing Plant, Cooleemee, 1932-1948; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Dye and Finishing Plant, 1945-1947 (Box 15)
  - Dyes: Cooleemee Dye Boss, C.C. Miller, 1909-1910; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Ellerbee Creek and dye branch pollution, 1914-1915; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Employee accidents: releases and court settlements before Workman's Compensation Law, 1903-1929 (Box 15)
  - Exhibits, 1901-1902 (Box 15)
  - Farm Relief (McNary-Haugen Bill), 1920s (Box 15)
  - Financial statements, 1897-1945 and undated (Box 15)
  - Financial statements: Earnings and surplus, 1892-1957 (Box 15)
  - Financial statements: Expense and income, Mill 1, 1922 Mar. 31 (Box 16)
  - Financial statistics: Comparative figures, 1909-1920 (Box 16)
    For Erwin Cotton Mills, Durham Cotton Manufacturing Co., Pearl Cotton Mills, Locke Cotton Mills, Alpine Cotton Mills, and Oxford Cotton Mills
  - Financial statistics table, 1892-1954 (Box 64)
    Oversize.
  - Financial study of Erwin Cotton Mills, 1937 (Box 16)
  - Flint and Co. and Yarn Mills consolidation (Alpine and Oxford Mills), 1928 (Box 16)
  - Government contracts renegotiation papers, 1942-1945; 6 folders (Box 16)
  - Government reports: Affiliated corporations, questionnaires, and stockholder lists, 1917-1921 (Box 17)
  - Government reports: Bureau of the Census, 1909-1914 (Box 17)
  - Government reports: Bureau of the Census, 1947-1959; 8 folders (Box 17)
  - Government reports: Dept. of Commerce, 1946-1952 (Box 18)
  - Government reports: Federal Tariff Commission Working Papers, 1941 (Box 18)
  - Government reports: Federal Trade Commission, 1940-1952 (Box 18)
  - Government reports: Federal Trade Commission Agricultural Income Inquiry, 1936 (Box 18)
  - Government reports: N.C. Corporation Commission, 1901-1903 (Box 18)
  - Government reports: N.C. Corporation Commission, 1904-1932; 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Government reports: N.C. Corporation Commission, 1901-1903 (Box 64)
  - Government reports: N.C. Dept. of Labor and Printing, 1910, 1913-1915 (Box 18)
  - Government reports: Office of Price Information, 1941-1944; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Government reports: Treasury Dept., Dept. of Commerce, and Federal Trade Commission, 1953-1961 (Box 19)
  - Government reports: War Production Board-Value of Inventories, 1940-1942 (Box 19)
  - Graham, Irwin P. and Cooleemee Mills, 1935 (Box 19)
  - Group Insurance Plan, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Harnett County land sales, 1920 (Box 19)
  - Haw River property options, 1901-1907 (Box 19)
  - Inventories, 1906-1919 and undated (Box 19)
    Including some exhibits.
  - Inventories, 1930-1932 (Box 19)
  - Inventories, 1965 July 3 (Box 19)
  - Inventories, 1965 July 3 (Box 20)
  - Inventories, 1966 Jan. (Box 20)
  - Inventories, 1966-1967 (Box 21)
  - Inventories: LIFO, 1940-1957; 5 folders (Box 22)
  - Inventories: LIFO Miscellaneous Information, 1940-1953; 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Inventories: Mill 3, 1949 (Box 22)
  - Inventories: Standard procedure for machinery repairs and supplies, findings, and oil perpetual inventory, 1947 (Box 22)
  - Jackson-Fitchette Drug Co., Erwin, N.C., dissolution, 1928 (Box 23)
  - Journal entries, 1965-1967 (Box 23)
  - Labor, 1916-1917 (Box 23)
  - Locke Cotton Mills: financial statements, 1910-1920 (Box 23)
  - Measuring tables and apparatus, cutter and marker devices, and seam and defect detectors: Licensing agreement with Perry family and other papers, 1936-1938; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Memorandum books, No. 4, 5, 7, 1923-1929 (Box 23)
    Continued from Price Books in Account Book series.
  - Memorandum books, No. 8-11, 1929-1933 (Box 24)
  - Memorandum books, No. 12, 14-16, 1933-1938 (Box 25)
  - Memorandum of Orders 1, 1933-1935 (Box 26)
  - Memorandum of Orders 2, 1936-1938 (Box 26)
  - Merchants National Bank, Philadelphia, PA: Financial report to, 1902 (Box 26)
    Photocopy.
  - Merchants National Bank, Philadelphia, PA: Financial report to, 1902 (Box 64)
  - Mill house sales in Durham, 1945-1946 (Box 26)
    Contracts and related papers, no. 1-177. 5 folders.
  - Mill house sales in Durham, 1945-1946 (Box 26)
    General papers.
  - Mill 2, Erwin, N.C.: Commissary litigation, 1904 (Box 27)
    R.L. Godwin vs. Erwin Cotton Mills
  - Mill 2: Notices served by J.A. Williams during construction, 1903 (Box 27)
  - Mill 2: Property acquisition, survey, map, etc., 1898-1899 (Box 27)
  - Mill 4, Durham, N.C.: Property options, 1909 (Box 27)
  - Minutes of Directors and Stockholders, 1892-1941 (Box 27)
    Scattered entries.
  - Miscellaneous papers and memoranda including a variety of financial statements, 1920-1937; 10 folders (Box 27)
  - North Durham land, 1907 (Box 27)
  - Notes receivable: Small loans to individuals, 1954-1955; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Notes receivable: Small loans to individuals, 1954-1959; 5 folders (Box 28)
  - Orders received, 1919 (Box 28)
  - Orders received and stock memoranda, 1923-1928 (Box 28)
  - Oxford Cotton Mills, 1908-1948 (Box 28)
  - Payroll: Employees over and under 16 years of age at Cooleemee Plant, 1910 (Box 29)
  - Payroll: Index of payroll records, 1936-1952 (Box 29)
    On film destroyed, 1965.
  - Payroll: List of salaried employees, 1920s or earlier (Box 29)
  - Personnel, 1915-1920 (Box 29)
  - Pricing, World War II, 1942-1944 (Box 29)
  - Production and equipment estimates, 1914 (Box 29)
  - Profit and loss, dividends, depreciation, sales, and payroll, 1910-1919 (Box 29)
  - Profit and loss, income and expense statements, and related papers, 1926-1944; 7 folders (Box 29)
  - Profit and loss, income and expense statements, and related papers, 1944-1946; 6 folders (Box 30)
  - Profit and loss, income and expense statements, and related papers, 1947-1949; 9 folders (Box 31)
  - Profit and loss, income and expense statements, and related papers, 1950-1953; 8 folders (Box 32)
  - Profit and loss, income and expense statements, and related papers, 1954-1958; 10 folders (Box 33)
  - Profit and loss, income and expense statements, and related papers, 1959-1963; 7 folders (Box 34)
  - Profit and loss, income and expense statements, and related papers, 1964; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Profit sharing, 1927 and 1936; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Profit sharing committee awards, 1916-1919 (Box 35)
  - Profit sharing committee awards, 1920-1923; 4 folders (Box 35)
  - Profit sharing miscellaneous papers, 1916-1919 (Box 35)
  - Railroads: Indemnity bonds for delivery of goods without bill of landing, 1935 (Box 36)
  - Real estate costs, 1953-1964 (Box 36)
  - Real estate disposals, 1958-1964; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Road petitions for route over Tate Survey, West Durham, 1909 (Box 36)
  - Sanforizing Licensing with Cluett, Peabody, and Co., 1932-1948 (Box 36)
  - Sewage line easements, Durham County, 1916; 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Slasher device by Thomas Ralph, 1912-1914 (Box 37)
  - Social security and unemployment compensation (federal and state), 1935-1944 (Box 37)
  - Social welfare in West Durham, 1928 and earlier (Box 37)
  - Stationary with print of first mill, 1890s (Box 37)
  - Stock summary figures, 1892-1927 (Box 37)
  - Stock transfer list, 1916-1917 (Box 37)
  - Supporting Papers for Journal Entries, 1949; 3 folders (Box 37)
  - Supporting Papers for Journal Entries, 1949; 8 folders (Box 38)
  - Supporting Papers for Journal Entries, 1950; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Taxation, 1937-1941 (Box 39)
  - Taxation: Ad Valorem taxes, 1946-1952; 8 folders (Box 39)
  - Taxation: Ad Valorem taxes, 1953-1962; 10 folders (Box 40)
  - Taxation: Additional 1918 income and profit taxes, 1924 (Box 41)
  - Taxation: Capital stock tax returns, 1917-1945; 2 folders (Box 41)
  - Taxation, 1932-1935 (Box 41)
    Cotton processing tax, floor stock tax, Sanforizing royalty, drawback on export waste shipments
  - Taxation: FICA taxes, 1941, 1943-1955; 4 folders (Box 41)
  - Taxation: FICA taxes, 1956-1963 (Box 42)
  - Taxation: Franchise tax returns for Mississippi, 1951-1957 (Box 42)
  - Taxation: Franchise tax returns for N.C., 1934-1948, 1951-1957 (Box 42)
  - Taxation: Franchise tax returns for N.C. and Mississippi, 1958-1963 (Box 42)
  - Taxation: Income tax, 1894 (Box 42)
  - Taxation: Income tax, 1894 (Box 64)
  - Taxation: Income tax, 1909-1910, 1916-1918 (Box 42)
  - Taxation: Income tax withheld in N.C., 1960-1964 (Box 42)
  - Taxation: N.C. intangible personal property tax claims for refusals, 1941-1944 (Box 42)
  - Taxation: N.C. intangible personal property tax returns, 1938-1963; 3 folders (Box 42)
  - Taxation: Processing tax refund claims, 1933-1938; 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Taxation: Property tax, 1928 (Box 43)
  - Taxation: Property tax lists, 1892-1902 (Box 43)
  - Taxation: Property tax lists, 1893-1902 (Box 64)
  - Taxation: Property tax lists, Mill 2, 1903-1919; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Taxation: Property tax lists, Mill 3, 1907-1919; 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Taxation: Unemployment tax returns, 1945-1952 (Box 44)
    Includes related papers as early as 1939.
  - Taxation: Unemployment tax returns for Mississippi, 1948-1964 (Box 44)
  - Taxation: Unemployment tax returns for N.C., 1944-1964; 3 folders (Box 44)
  - Taxation: Unemployment tax returns for U.S., 1945-1963 (Box 44)
  - Taxation: Unjust enrichment tax returns, 1935-1936 (Box 44)
  - Telephone line right of way deeds, Durham to Erwin, N.C., 1903-1908 (Box 45)
  - Tenant farmers, 1921 (Box 45)
  - Trial balances: Mills 1, 2, 3, 1908 Dec. 31 (Box 45)
  - Wage charts for 1944 briefs, 4 folders (Box 45)
  - Water pipeline and electric power line to New Hope Creek, 1910 (Box 45)
  - Water reservoir site land purchase on New Hope Creek (Patterson's Mill site), 1909; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Water supply survey on New Hope Creek, 1909 (Box 45)
  - Water supply survey on New Hope Creek, 1909 (Box 64)
  - Watts, Gerard S., estate: Distribution of stocks and bonds, 1914; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Weekly financial reports, 1959 Oct. 3-1960; 3 folders (Box 45)
  - Weekly financial reports, 1961-1964; 7 folders (Box 46)
  - Weekly financial reports, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Woodward Baldwin and Co., interest settlement statements, 1954-1964 (Box 47)
  - Young Mercantile Co., West Durham, N.C., 1904 (Box 47)
- Labor Relations series, 1933-1952; 4
  The Labor Relations series focuses upon the company's relationship with its workers, the Textile Workers Union of America, and the federal government. Files largely date from the late 1930s and early 1940s. The series documents strikes and extensive negotiations with employees, as well as contracts, memoranda, correspondence, wage charts, labor agreements, and other materials. There is also material from the United Textile Workers challenging the Textile Workers Union of America in 1951 and 1952.
  - Bulletins, news items, etc., 1933-1940 and undated (Box 47)
  - CIO meetings and letters on contract, 1938-1940 (Box 47)
  - CIO non-contract meetings, 1940 (Box 47)
  - Contracts submitted by the CIO, 1938-1939 (Box 47)
  - Contracts submitted by Erwin, 1938-1939 (Box 47)
  - Contracts under consideration, 1940 (Box 48)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 and undated (Box 48)
  - Election of Feb. 9, 1938, 1937-1938 (Box 48)
  - Labor's Charter of Rights, 1935 (Box 48)
  - Letters to managers, 1937-1939 (Box 48)
  - McLendon, L.P., 1940 (Box 48)
  - Meetings on contract, 1940 (Box 48)
  - Memoranda, 1940 (Box 48)
  - Memoranda on contract, 1937-1940 (Box 48)
  - National Labor Relations Board, 1940 (Box 48)
  - National War Labor Board, 1942 (Box 48)
  - National War Labor Board, 1942, 1945 (Box 48)
  - National War Labor Board wage case, 1942 (Box 48)
  - Perkins, William Robertson, 1940 (Box 49)
  - Shop Committee meetings, 1937-1940 (Box 49)
  - Strike of June 1939, 1939 and undated (Box 49)
  - Strike of March 1940 (Box 49)
  - Textile Steering Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 49)
  - Textile Workers Union of America, 1939-1946 (Box 49)
  - Textile Workers Union of America: Negotiations, 1941; 3 folders (Box 49)
  - Textile Workers Union of America: Negotiations, 1941 (Box 49)
  - Textile Workers Union of America: Negotiations of 1941 background material, 1938-1941 (Box 50)
  - Textile Workers Union of America: Statement in the matter of the cotton-rayon industry, 1944 (Box 50)
  - Textile Workers Union of America vs. United Textile Workers, 1951-1952 (Box 50)
  - Tobacco industry labor agreements, 1937-1940 (Box 50)
  - Unemployment compensation hearing, 1940 Apr. 9 (Box 50)
  - Various CIO and AFL contracts, 1937-1941 (Box 50)
  - Wage charts, 1943 (Box 50)
  - Wage survey in finishing industry, 1941 (Box 50)
- William Allen Erwin series, 1871-1932; 5
  The William Allen Erwin series consists mainly of files representing his personal and family interests and business. Also included are correspondence files that contain both personal and business correspondence regarding the mill and textile industries. The correspondence largely dates from 1928. Notable topics include: national and state issues; North Carolina parishes of the Protestant Episcopal Church; St. Mary' School in Raleigh; correspondence regarding his salary in 1920 with James B. Duke; St. Joseph's Episcopal Church; real estate; house and dormitory construction; the textile industry; University of North Carolina; Duke University; politics; and hunting dogs. Correspondents include Albert Anderson, Thomas Hall Battle, Martin E. Boyer Jr., Joseph Blount Cheshire, Heriot Clarkson, Benjamin Newton Duke, H.R. Fitzgerald, John A. Law, Edwin Anderson Penick, Edward Knox Powe, James Augustus Thomas, Hobart Brown Upjohn, and members of the Erwin and Holt families.
  - Alamance County property, 1871-1899 (Box 50)
  - Aldert Smedes estate, 1892-1894 (Box 50)
  - Automobiles, buggies, etc., 1900s (Box 50)
  - Bank of Harnett, 1915, 1928 (Box 50)
  - Biographical material about William A. Erwin and John Locke Erwin, 1927, 1932 (Box 50)
  - Blakeley Silver, undated (Box 50)
  - Burke County property, 1891 (Box 50)
  - Business miscellany, 1916-1928 (Box 51)
  - Capital apartments elevator, 1927-1928 (Box 51)
  - Chapel of the Cross, Chapel Hill: Contract for Skinner organ, 1924 (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, 1893-1927; 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, 1928-1931 and undated (Box 51)
    Notes on correspondents and topics
  - Correspondence, 1928 Jan.-Mar.; 5 folders (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Apr.-Sept.; 11 folders (Box 52)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Sept.-1931 and undated; 10 folders (Box 53)
  - Dogs and dog shows, 1924-1930 and undated (Box 54)
  - Duke family, 1919 and undated (Box 54)
  - Fidelity Bank, 1927-1929 (Box 54)
  - Financial papers, 1894-1929 and undated; 4 folders (Box 54)
  - Financial papers: check stubs, 1917-1921; 7 volumes (Box 54)
  - Food Administration, Durham County, 1918 (Box 54)
  - Gardner, Oliver Max, 1920 (Box 54)
  - Genealogy and family information, Erwin, Phifer, etc., undated (Box 54)
  - Haywood, Ernest, Law offices, 1925-1928 (Box 55)
  - Hillcrest and St. Joseph's Episcopal Church contracts and specifications, 1907-1908 (Box 55)
  - Holt, Dr. William P. and Co. Hospital at Erwin, N.C., 1927-1928 (Box 55)
  - Horses and horse shows, 1928 and undated (Box 55)